<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Home</title>
    <link>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabase installation on AWS EC2</title>
      <link>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/aws_metabase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/aws_metabase/</guid>
      <description>This post demonstrates the process of installation of Metabase Business Intelligence Tool on an AWS EC2 instance.
Metabase is an open source Business Intelligence Tool used to query databases for individuals and companies with or without knowledge of SQL.
&amp;lsquo;Metabase is a simple and powerful analytics tool which lets anyone learn and make decisions from their company’s data. No technical knowledge required!&amp;rsquo;
 Learn more about the Metabase at: https://www.metabase.com/ Official Installtion documentation of Metabase at: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InfluxDB OSS installation locally or on AWS EC2</title>
      <link>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/aws_influxdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/aws_influxdb/</guid>
      <description>This post demonstrates the process of installing the OSS version of InfluxDB locally or on an AWS EC2 instance, running Ubuntu 18.04/20.04.
InfluxDB is a time series database designed to handle high write and query loads. Sensor data used in IoT applications can be logged in this time series DB.
&amp;lsquo;InfluxDB is meant to be used as a backing store for any use case involving large amounts of timestamped data, including DevOps monitoring, application metrics, IoT sensor data, and real-time analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node-RED installation locally or on AWS EC2</title>
      <link>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/aws_nodered/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/aws_nodered/</guid>
      <description>This post demonstrates the process of installing Node-RED locally or on an AWS EC2 instance, running Ubuntu 18.04/20.04.
Node-RED is a programming tool for wiring together hardware devices, APIs and online services in the Internet of Things domain. It provides a browser based pick and place block approach to wire the different components &amp;amp; blocks.
Node-RED is built on Node.js and the flows created in Node-RED are stored in the form of JSON.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LAMP Stack on AWS EC2</title>
      <link>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/aws_lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/aws_lamp/</guid>
      <description>This post gives you a quick writeup on running a LAMP stack on AWS EC2 instance.
LAMP is the acronym of
 Linux Apache Web Server MariaDB (Relational database) PHP (Serverside language)  Steps to follow to install a LAMP Stack on AWS EC2
 Create an EC2 instance with the following specifications  Ubuntu 18.04 Server LTS OS Minimum 1 vCPU &amp;amp; 2 GB of RAM Minimum 8 GB of SSD In Security policy,  Open SSH Port 22 to be accessed only from your local machine Open HTTP Port 80 &amp;amp; HTTPS Port 443 to be accessed from any IP (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/test-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/test-blog/</guid>
      <description>Hugo 0.24 Released: Big archetype update + @Netlify _redirects etc. file supporthttps://t.co/X94FmYDEZJ #gohugo #golang @spf13 @bepsays
&amp;mdash; GoHugo.io (@GoHugoIO) June 21, 2017    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme Demo</title>
      <link>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/theme-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jithinisaac.dblabs.in/posts/theme-demo/</guid>
      <description>Style Demoh1 Headingh2 Headingh3 Headingh4 Headingh5 Headingh6 Heading This is bold text
This is bold text
This is italic text
This is italic text
Deleted text
This is text with inline math $\sum_{n=1}^{\infty} 2^{-n} = 1$ and with math blocks:
$$ \sum_{n=1}^{\infty} 2^{-n} = 1 $$</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>